So... what do you think?
During the time between last night
and this morning after it stopped snowing,
an adult male came by and left.
-Let's check out inside.
-Yeah.
The backpack is gone.
And the box with the coal and stove.
He took them away.
Hey, who are you talking about?
The real killer.
A man who committed a murder
in the next town over
and got away with it.
And he's trying
to do the same thing in our town.
I finally told them.
It's just a guess I made,
after I saw the coal
and the contents in the backpack.
You think I'm making too big of a leap?
But I'm...
I'm scared
that someone I know will be killed.
Or maybe get arrested after being framed
for a crime they didn't commit.
It might just seem...
like I'm playing detective, but...
I don't mind playing detective.
I've got a feeling that hunch of yours
will lead us somewhere.
I'm going to choose to believe you.
Me, too.
I want to believe you, too.
Thanks.
So, this is what friendship is?
WE ARE LOOKING FOR AYA NAKANISHI
SHIRATORI REARRESTED
IN CONNECTION TO AYA'S MURDER
In the first timeline's 1988...
SHIRATORI FOODS
I should have been able to help him.
I could have...
I should have been able to...
save him.
I should've been able to save him...
I don't want to feel that way ever again.
You like Wonderguy?
Here.
Thanks.
You can have it.
I was gonna throw it away.
I thought I bought it myself.
I guess Yuuki gave it to me.
Thank you, Yuuki.
So, did you need something?
Yeah.
Yuuki,
do you know a girl named Aya Nakanishi?
Yeah, I do.
She's always alone in the park
by the river.
So, since she's always reading by herself
and looked lonely,
I tried talking to her once.
But she wouldn't really open up to me.
Just as I thought.
Yuuki always tries to talk to kids
who look like they're lonely.
Just like he did with me and Kayo.
That's so like Yuuki.
I said it aloud.
A red fire burns ablaze
Don't lose, stand up
Now that I think about it,
even as an adult I'd put on this record
whenever I wanted to think.
His loving heart is his weapon
A hero who protects you
The killer targets children
who are often alone
for long periods of time.
Aya Nakanishi definitely falls
into that category.
First thing,
I need to make sure she's not alone.
But she goes
to a different school than me.
How do I do this?
HAMANASU CRAM SCHOOL
Let's see.
It ends at 6:30 p.m.
Keyboard lessons at four p.m.,
then she spends some time on a bench
by the old lighthouse,
and then cram school at five p.m.
It sure is a busy schedule.
Satoru,
how did you find a loner like her?
That's some real detective work.
Well,
I thought I might as well do it right.
I'll follow her when she's done
and find out where she lives.
If the killer attempts to make contact,
it will most likely be when
she's walking home from cram school.
Satoru!
Oh, my God, perfect timing.
It's so heavy. Come help me.
-I can't believe this timing.
Why did you buy so much at once?
Because they were on sale.
Satoru.
Want a ride?
Oh, that way, that way.
You really saved us, Mr. Yashiro.
My mother really went overboard.
-I bet I looked like a superhero.
-Yeah.
Hey, Mr. Yashiro.
Why don't you get married?
What?!
Where'd that come from, Satoru?
Maybe I've gotten too cautious
after going through a bad experience.
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I don't mind the question.
-Then can I ask you something else?
-Sure.
How do you approach a girl you don't know,
who you want to be friends with?
Well, let's see.
I'm rather cautious,
so, the first thing I'd try to do is
to get her guard down.
Get her guard down?
Yeah. In other words,
you show off your good side.
Like in my case,
I'm good at sports, I'm good at cooking.
And I'm a public servant.
Use whatever you can.
If she expresses any interest
in any of them, she'll let down her guard.
I see.
I know I can always count on you.
Oh, I said it aloud.
-Satoru, grab me some candy.
-Sure.
-Here.
-Thanks.
What have those guys been up to lately?
Yeah. All three of them
have been acting suspicious.
She's alone again today.
What do you wanna do?
I don't care if she thinks I'm weird.
I'll try talking to her.
I just need to engage her
before it's too late.
Hello.
I'm Satoru Fujinuma
from Mikoto Elementary.
You're Aya Nakanishi, aren't you?
Have we met?
No.
Hey, what book are you reading?
I like reading, too.
It's William Shakespeare's King Lear.
Lear?
That's a pretty hard book you're reading.
Oh, I remember you now.
You're the kids who are always sneaking
into the building across the river.
Our secret base.
I guess you can clearly see it
from this side.
Secret base?
Why are boys so childish?
-Well, I have cram school now.
-Wait!
Secret bases are a man's dream.
Come see for yourself sometime.
Then you'll understand.
I don't see how anybody
would find that fun.
You guys are weirdos.
That couldn't have gone worse.
All I have to do is make sure
she's not alone.
How could it be this hard?
Satoru!
You stupid?
Just like our experiment two days ago,
lenses that are thicker in the middle...
Kayo came back.
They're allowing her to commute here
from her grandmother's by bus.
Kayo said Mr. Yashiro
helped arrange everything.
The light hits the lens and bends,
gathering at a point. The focal point.
And the distance from the lens
to the focal point
is called the focal length.
We haven't been
to the secret base in a while.
-Yeah, let's go, then.
-Yeah.
Satoru, let's go by the secret base.
We can bring Hinazuki.
Secret base...
Now that I think about it,
I haven't gone to our secret base
at all since the Revival.
MISSING BOY, HIROMI SUGITA
FIFTH GRADE BOY, POSSIBLY KIDNAPPED
In the first timeline's 1988...
that is where Hiromi's body was found.
In this timeline,
the secret base should be safe
from the crime.
Yeah. That's a good idea. Let's go.
Hey, we're all going by the base.
You're invited, Hinazuki.
Yeah.
There.
You really like places like this.
All boys do.
-Satoru.
-What is it?
It's almost four p.m.
Yeah, it's okay.
See?
We can see the lighthouse from here.
She hasn't come yet.
All right.
Who's there?
I decided
to come check your secret base out.
Welcome to our secret base.
Come on in.
-Move, Osamu.
-What? Why do I gotta move?
Thanks for having me.
-Let's play Othello.
-Okay.
I'm pretty good, you know.
Go easy on me.
It'll be fun.
Yes, I'm out.
What do you like to do?
I like to skate.
You got me.
I guess she was drawn
to his boyish charms.
From the looks of it,
Kazu feels the same.
It looks like we unexpectedly
figured out a way to reduce
Aya Nakanishi's time alone.
So, do you plan
to stop playing detective now?
No.
I can't let it end here.
Misato is the worst.
Yeah, totally.
Kayo.
Wanna go to the science center today?
Can we stop somewhere first?
I guess during the day,
it just looks like a plain, bald tree.
You stupid?
Hold on.
There's something I need to say to you.
What is it?
Thank you.
For leading me out of that place.
You're my...
You're my hero.
Say something.
Get back here.
What I'm doing now is not a waste of time.
I truly believed that.
By the way, Satoru...
Have you noticed
Misato has been alone lately?
What? Is it since the incident
with the lunch money?
I'm a little worried.
Okay. Let's try talking to her on Monday.
-I'm home.
-Welcome home.
Come get warm.
Hello. I'm Sawada,
a reporter for TV Ishikari.
I'm a friend of your mother's,
and I came to talk.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
What's gotten into you?
Would it be okay if I was part
of your conversation, too?
Satoru, are you interested
in becoming a reporter or something?
Something like that.
By the way, Mr. Sawada,
why did you come to our town?
Well...
That's...
Because I thought the person
I was looking for might be here in town.
Are you talking about...
the culprit in the unsolved crimes?
Yes.
-A serial child killer.
-Sawada.
The culprit targets grade school children.
Better that he knows.
There's been one case in Chitose,
and two cases in Sapporo
of young girls being murdered.
That many?
Yes.
A suspect has been arrested
in all of the cases,
but they all deny the allegations.
They swear they're innocent.
So, you think
that the killer is still out there?
Yes.
Criminals like this can't stop themselves.
If the killer is in this town,
it won't be long...
before an incident happens here.
MARCH 14TH (MONDAY)
I might be late tonight.
Fine, but give me a call
when you know you'll be home.
Especially after what Sawada said.
Okay.
-Thanks for the food.
-Yup. Okay.
-Bye.
-Bye, now.
This area gets very little precipitation.
Anybody know where this is?
Since today's the 14th,
we'll go with Takahashi, number 14.
The killer is likely looking
for a new target
to replace the ones I've saved.
I'm sure it's someone very close by.
WALK QUIETLY IN THE HALLS
Do you think we can be friends?
What?
I mean, we both walk
in the same direction to go home.
What's wrong with you?
Sorry.
I wasn't any help at all.
That's not true.
She might not show it,
but I'm pretty sure Misato
doesn't hate you anymore.
You think so?
Yeah. I'll try talking to her next.
Misato said she was going
to go cheer on the hockey team.
Got it. See you later.
Give it all you got!
Let's go, Mikoto Elementary!
You can do it!
Let's go!
Koichi! You don't get food if you lose!
SHIRATORI FOODS
You can do it!
Don't lose!
You better not lose!
You can do it!
Go, go, go!
Don't lose!
You can do it!
-Come on!
-You can do it!
Go, go, go!
Nice one!
Get it!
Keep pushing them!
RESTROOM
EMERGENCY EXIT
Shiratori?
That's Yuuki's family's truck.
It can't be.
-Satoru? What's up? The bathroom's--
-Mr. Yashiro, great timing.
There's something I have to check now.
Can you help me?
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto